Hollander, Louis Papers 5643
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Louis Hollander Papers
1914-1965
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Hollander, Louis
5643
11 cubic feet
11 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Letters, correspondence, convention proceedings, clippings
3338537
Scope and Contents
Boxes 11, 12, 13 contain photographs and are listed under #5643 P
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5643 P: Louis Hollander Photographs
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 05, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, June 06, 2019
Labor unions -- Officials and employees; Hollander, Louis, 1893-; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America
3338537
- Correspondence: Miscellaneous letters, 1919-1949 (6 folders Government letters, 1934-1949 (7 folders) Cornell University, 1945-1954 (2 folders) Board of Regents, 1945-1946 Education, 1946-1951 Civil Defense, 1949-1951. (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1919-1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    1919-1938, 1942-1944
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Government Letters, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Government Letters, 1934-1942 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    1934-1935, 1937-1938, 1942
  - Government Letters, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Government Letters, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Government Letters, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Government Letters, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Government Letters, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Cornell University Ithaca, N.Y., 1949-1954 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Board of Regents(Education), 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence on Education, 1946-1951 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence- Cornell University School of Industrial and Labor Relations, 1945-1949 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Civil Defense, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Correspondence: Government letters, 1951-1953 Sidney Hillman Health Center, 1951 NYS CIO Council, 1951-1953 Europe-Israel, 1951, 1953 National Conference of Christians & Jews, 1951-1952 Miscellaneous letters, 1950-1957 Regents Committee, 1950-1954 White House (Box 2)
  - Government Letters, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Sidney Hillman Health Center Agreement & Declaration of Trust-Letters Miscellaneous Letters, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - New York State CIO Council, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Speeches and notes, some correspondence
  - Europe Israel, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Letters 1950 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - University of the State of New York Regents Committee on High School Readjustment, 1950-1954 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: White House Conference on Education, Washington D.C., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    June-December 1955
  - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Alcoa Power Hearing, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Albany, New York June 14, 1955
  - Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    July 1956-August 1957
- Biographical sketches, speeches, NYS Convention Proceedings, 1954. (Box 3)
  - N.Y. Post Biographical Sketch Jewish American, Speeches, 1950-1953 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    September 3, 1950 July 3, 1953
  - Proceedings of the 13th Annual Convention New York State--CIO, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Hotel Statler, Buffalo, N.Y. September 4-6, 1952
  - Proceeding 14th Annual Convention New York State CIO Council, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    September 24-26, 1953 Lido Terrace Long Beach, NY
  - New York State AFL-CIO Convention Proceedings, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Hotel Commodore September 10-12, 1962 New York city
  - Proceedings Constitutional convention of the New York State Industrial Union Council, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    August 23-25, 1956 Old Fellows Hall Albany, N.Y.
  - Proceedings of the 15th Annual Constitutional Convention of the New York State CIO, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    September 9-11, 1954 Hotel Ten Eyck Albany, N.Y.
- Clippings. (Box 4)
  - Clippings 1, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Clippings 2, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Clippings 3, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Clippings 4, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Clippings 5, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Political Clipp Nov. 1937-June 1938 (2 scrapbooks). (Box 5)
  - Louis Hollander, American Labor Party Councilman Scrapbook Clippings, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Louis Hollander Scrapbook Clippings 2, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Scrapbook NYS Convention, CIO, 1947; Proceedings, 1947; Miscellaneous publications; The Hat and General Clippings, 1952-1953; Dewey's Labor Day Message, 1947 (clippings). (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook Clippings Taft-Hartley, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Eighth Annual Convention of the New York State CIO Council, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Saratoga Springs, New York September 4-6, 1947
  - 17th Biennial National Convention of Women's American ORT, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    October 14-17, 1963 New York Hilton Hotel, New York City
  - Summary of Information on Projects and Activities in the Field of Rehabilitation of the Disabled During 1963 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - The Johnson Foundation, a Program Report (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - The Hat and General Clippings, 1950-1953 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    April 1950-February 1953
  - Dewey's Labor Day Message, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Annual Report Governor's Committee on "Employ the Physically Handicapped", 1959 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Clipping Scrapbooks: 1943-1948 CIO Clippings; 1947 Congressional Hearing On Hi Cost of Living; 1948 Clippings on Action by State CIO Third Party and Henry Wallace; 1949 National CIO Convention, Oregon and State CIO Convention,Syracuse; 1949 Saratoga State CIO Convention Political (Box 7)
  - Clippings CIO, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Clippings CIO, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - CIO Clippings, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 1946 CIO Convention (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Lake Placid, New York
  - 1946 Clippings (Box 7, Folder 5)
    May to December 31
  - Clippings 1946 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    January to April 30
  - CIO Clippings, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    March to August
  - Clippings, 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    November 1947-1948
  - 1948 Clippings on Action by State CIO on Third Party and Henry Wallace (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Congressional Hearing on High Cost of Living, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - National CIO Convention, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Portland, Oregon November 22-26, 1948, general clippings
  - Saratoga State CIO Convention Political News, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    September-December 1949
- Clipping Scrapbooks: City CIO, 1949-1950; General CIO Clippings 1949-1950; Old Pension-NYS Publishers Associated Meeting Board of Examiners 1945-1950; State CIO Convention and NYS Election Campaign, 1950; Clippings, 1951; Governor's Nomination and Election (Box 8)
  - City CIO Clippings, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    March 1949-Jan 1950
  - General CIO Clippings, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    December 1949-January 1950
  - Old Age Pension N.Y. State Publishers Associated Meeting Board of Examiners, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - State CIO Convention, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Statler Hotel, New York City October 5-7, 1950
  - State CIO PAC & State CIO Convention April 1950-December 31,1950 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    January 1951
  - Governor's Nomination & Election N.Y. State, 1950-1951 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Sept. 1950-January 1951
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews Cornell University, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    July 26-28, 1951 & other clippings
  - New York State CIO Convention, Legislative and General News Clippings, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    Lake Placid, N.Y. September 6-8, 1951
- Clipping Scrapbooks: NYS CIO Convention, 1952; General Clippings, 1935; Convention 1953 and Political Clippings 1953; General Clippings 1954 NUS CIO Convention 1954, Political and General 1954; General Clippings 1955; General C 1956; NYS CIO Convention 1956 (Box 9)
  - Clippings New York State CIO Convention, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Buffalo N.Y. September 4-6, 1952
  - General Clippings, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Clippings of: N.Y. State CIO Convention & Political Clippings, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    September 24-26, 1953 Lido Beach Hotel, Long Island
  - General Clippings, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Clippings of N.Y. State CIO Convention & Political & General Clippings, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    held at the Ten Eyck Hotel, Albany, N.Y.
  - Clippings, N.Y. State CIO Convention & Political & General Clippings, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    held at the Ten Eyck Hotel, Albany, N.Y. September 9-11,1954
  - General Clippings, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - General Clippings, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - General Clippings, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    June 1955-December 1955
  - General Clippings, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, New York State CIO Convention, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    August 23-25, 1956 Hotel Ten Eyck, Albany N.Y. & General Campaign Clippings
- Clipping Scrapbooks: 1957 General Clippings; NYS CIO Convention, 1956; General Clippings 1957-1958; General Clippings 1958-1959; C] Merger of State CIO and AFL, 1958; Policy of Po.J Action 1959-1962; General Clippings 1962-1964. (Box 10)
  - General Clippings, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    1957
  - Clippings, New York State CIO Convention, 1956-1957 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    August 23-25 Albany N.Y.
  - General Clippings, 1957-1958 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    December 1957-January 1958
  - General Clippings, 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - General Clippings, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    July 1958
  - Merger of N.Y. State CIO & N.Y. State CFL, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, Merger of N.Y. State CIO & N.Y. State AFL, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, Policy of Political Action, 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    September 1959-1960
  - Clippings, Policy of Political Action, 1959-1962 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - General Clippings, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - General Clippings, 1962-1964 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous publications. (Box 14)
  - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1914-1964 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 2)